Guide to the Office of Multicultural Affairs Records 1987-2004
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
- Presentations, 1991-2004; Series VII
  Series VII pertains to presentations made by Lee for campus departments, student organizations, orientation of new faculty members, public schools, state agencies, companies, and new student orientation programs. Also documenting conference addresses and panelist participation at public forums, this series consists of correspondence, flyers, publications, and speech notes.
  - Academic Advisors Workshop, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Advisors Brown Bag-Tips for Working Effectively with Diverse Students, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Albany General Hospital Home Care and Hospice, 1992 (Box 9)
  - American Council on Education Conferences, 1994-2001; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 2001 (Box 9)
  - Asian American/Pacific Islander HIV Prevention, 2002-2003 (Box 9)
  - Asian Nights Celebration (OSU), 1993-1995 (Box 9)
  - Asian/Pacific American Welcome Reception, 2004 (Box 9)
  - Asian Youth Leadership Conference, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Associated Students of OSU (ASOSU) Retreats, 1992-1995 (Box 9)
  - Barometer Staff Diversity Training, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Barometer Training Workshop-Minorities and the Media, 2001 (Box 9)
  - Behavioral Interviewing Workshop: Search Committee for the Director of Community and Diversity, 2004 (Box 9)
  - Benton County Commission on Children and Families, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Cambodian/Laotian New Year Celebration, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Cambodian New Year Celebration, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Campus Tour Staff Training, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Career Information Days, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Coalition for Cross-Cultural Outreach Conferences, 2000-2001 (Box 9)
  - College Foundation Development Officers Meeting, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Conference and Event Coordinator Network-Cultural Awareness Training Session, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Corvallis High School-Multicultural Awareness Week, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Corvallis Police Department, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Crescent Valley High School, undated (Box 9)
  - Cultural Center Staff Retreat, 1996
    - Retreat Materials (Box 9)
    - Retreat Notes (Map-case *)
  - Cultural Diversity Institute-WICHE Program, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Dean’s Council (OSU), 1998 (Box 9)
  - Difficult Dialogues Series-Gender (OSU), 2001 (Box 9)
  - Discrimination and Hate Community Forum, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Emery Parish Exhibit-Public Forum Panel, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Ethical Issues in Academic Life Forum Panelist, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Florence (Oregon) Diversity Day, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Gay/Lesbian/Bisexual Resource Fair, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Golden Key Honorary Society Chapter Installation Keynote Address, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Government-to-Government Education Cluster Meeting, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Honors College Fall Forum, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Housing Coordinators Training, 1995 (Box 9)
  - InterACTION Project Staff, 1996 (Box 9)
  - International Refugee Center of Oregon (IRCO) Annual Conference, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Introduction of Graduate at the Class of 2004 Lavender Graduation (Box 9)
  - Introductions of the Office of Multicultural Affairs to Campus, 1991-1992 (Box 9)
  - Ism: College Students-Diversity and Community Panel, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - Japanese Nights Celebrations, 1994-1996 (Box 9)
  - Kaiser Permanente Cultural Diversity Task Force, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Leslie Middle School (Salem) Bilingual Students, 1999-2000 (Box 9)
  - Linn-Benton Community College, 1997-2003 (Box 9)
  - Los Angeles Police Trial Verdict Open Forum, 1993 (Box 9)
  - McNair Scholars Graduation Address, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Menucha IV Conference-Diversity as Opportunity in Workplaces, Communities, and Schools, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Minority Business Students Association, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Mom’s Weekend-Cultural Diversity Breakfast, 1999 (Box 9)
  - NAACP-Corvallis Branch, 2001 (Box 9)
  - New Faculty (OSU) Orientations, 1993-1999 (Box 9)
  - New Student Orientation Programs, 1993-1994 (Box 9)
  - Northwest Coalition Against Malicious Harassment Conference, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Northwest Women in Educational Administration Meeting, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Old Mill Center for Children and Families, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Oregon Commission on Asian Affairs, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Oregon Commission on Hispanic Affairs, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Oregon Bilingual Summer Institute, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Oregon Institute on Ethnic Diversity Seminar, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Oregon School Age Care Alliance Conference, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Oregon State Bar-Debtor/Creditor Section Annual Meeting, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Oregon Supreme Court Task Force on Racial/Ethnic Issues in the Judicial System-Ethnic Sensitivity Training, 1992 (Box 9)
  - OSU College of Ag. Sciences Ambassadors-Training Session, 1996 (Box 9)
  - OSU Conference and Event Coordinator Network, 2003 (Box 9)
  - OSU Mini College, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - OSU Office Personnel Association Luncheon, 1998 (Box 9)
  - OSU Pow Wow, 2001 (Box 9)
  - OSU Public Forum Panels-Is Affirmative Action Reverse Discrimination?, 2002-2003 (Box 9)
  - OSU Start Program Diversity Development Workshop, 1999 (Box 9)
  - OSU Woman of Achievement Award-Acceptance Speech, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Oregon Women in Higher Education Conference, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Pacific Association for Cooperative Education Conference-Keynote Speaker, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Pi Lambda Theta Honorary Society-Portland Chapter, 1993 (Box 10)
  - Professional Faculty Leadership Association (OSU)-Holiday Celebrations, 2003 (Box 10)
  - Public Hearing on Oregon State Senate Bills 338 and 339 (Multicultural Education Programs and Policies), 1997 (Box 10)
  - Race and Class Symposium in Portland, 1999 (Box 10)
  - Reader’s Theater-Climate for Faculty from Historically Underrepresented Groups, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Recreational Sports Dept. Staff Orientation, 1993 (Box 10)
  - Rotary Club-Corvallis, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Sackett Hall Dormitory Lecture on “Name-Calling, Labels, and Epithets”, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Salem-Keizer Public School District-Multicultural Conference, 1997 (Box 10)
  - SMILE Program Teacher Orientation, 1999 (Box 10)
  - State Management Association-Affirmative Action Forum, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Student Employee Supervisors, 1997 (Box 10)
  - Summer Orientation and Admission Program (SOAP), 1993-1996 (Box 10)
  - Teacher and Counselor Education Licensure Faculty Meeting-Racism Panel, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Title IX and Women of Color Panel, 1998 (Box 10)
  - Ukrainian Women’s Leadership Program, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Upward Bound, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Western Association of University Publications Managers Meeting, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Western Oregon University-Responding to Cultural Diversity Panel, 1997 (Box 10)
  - Women’s Leadership Conference Panelist, 2003 (Box 10)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1992-2003; Series VIII (Box 10)
  The clippings in series VIII relate to the establishment of the office and Lee’s appointment as director, the Difference, Power, and Discrimination Program, the OSU Cultural Centers, incidents of racism and homophobia, and diversity education events on campus. The articles and editorials were clipped from the Daily Barometer, Corvallis Gazette-Times, and the Oregonian.
- Notes, 1992-1996; Series IX (Box 10)
  Series IX is made up of notes taken by Phyllis Lee recording various meetings and interviews with faculty of color on campus and OSU administrators.
- Subject Files, 1991-2004; Series X
  The subject files in Series X are comprised of materials originating from a variety of off-campus organizations and governmental agencies oriented toward human rights, racial advocacy, social services, and educational equity. Also documented in this series are conferences and workshops held at OSU and off-campus that were not organized by the Office of Multicultural Affairs. Made up of correspondence, publications, reports, and notes, these files also explore minority student statistical profiles, Martin Luther King Jr. Service Day, state legislation, and other universities’ diversity plans.
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 1994 (Box 10)
  - Asian American Baseline Essays, 1992-1993 (Box 10)
  - Asian Pacific American Network of Oregon, 1998-2001 (Box 10)
  - Ayala Foundation for Educational Equity, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Benton Community Health Center, 2003 (Box 10)
  - Benton County Commission on Children and Families, 1996-2001 (Box 10)
  - Chaordic Organization, 1997 (Box 10)
  - Conferences, 1991-2001
    - Agricultural Comm. Dept. Retreat on Outreach to Hispanics (OSU), 1991 (Box 10)
    - American Missionaries and Social Change in China: An International Public Symposium, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Boundaries and Borderlands III: The Search for Recognition and Community in America, 1999 (Box 10)
    - Breaking Down Walls: Scholarship and Activism Among Lesbians, Gays, Bisexuals, and Friends, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Building Bridges: 5th Annual Multicultural Students Leadership Retreat, 1995 (Box 10)
    - Creative Ways of Finding and Keeping Faculty and Administrators of Color, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Environmental Justice: Burdens and Promise, 1995 (Box 10)
    - Improving Minority Adult Participation in Higher Education, 1992 (Box 10)
    - International Federation of Gender Education, 1996 (Box 10)
    - Japanese Americans and World War II: Lessons Past, Present, and Future-K-12 Educator’s Workshop (OSU), 1998 (Box 10)
    - Learning Technologies and Students of Color, 1997 (Box 10)
    - National Conference on Race and Ethnicity in American Higher Education, 2001 (Box 10)
    - Northwest Coalition Against Malicious Harassment, 1992 (Box 10)
    - Open Mind (Association for the Achievement of Cultural Diversity in Higher Education), 1993 (Box 10)
    - OSU Diversity Summit, 2001 (Box 10)
    - Pacific Northwest Students of Color, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Retaining Adult Students in Higher Education (video-conference), 1992 (Box 10)
    - We Can Get Along: A Blueprint for a Campus Unity (video-conference), 1993 (Box 10)
  - Consortium for American Indian Graduate Education, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Corvallis Area Chamber of Commerce, 2000-2001 (Box 10)
  - Corvallis-Benton County Economic Development Partnership Inc., 2001 (Box 10)
  - Diversity Related Activities and Historical Timeline at OSU, 1999-2000 (Box 10)
  - Inroads Inc., 1997 (Box 10)
  - Marketing and Publicity, 1999-2002 (Box 10)
  - Martin Luther King Jr. Citizen Memorial Award, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Martin Luther King Jr. Service Day Initiative, 1998 (Box 10)
  - MECHA (Movimiento Estudiantil Chicano de Aztlan) Student Group, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Metropolitan Human Rights Commission (Portland), 1994 (Box 10)
  - Multicultural Literacy Center-Corvallis, 2001 (Box 10)
  - National Asian Pacific-American Legal Consortium, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Native American Collaborative Institute, undated (Box 10)
  - Oregon Assembly for Black Affairs, 1993-1995 (Box 10)
  - Oregon Commission on Black Affairs, 1991-1994 (Box 10)
  - Oregon State Legislation: Senate Bill 103 (public school multicultural education policy), 1999 (Box 10)
  - Oregon State Police, 1994-2001 (Box 10)
  - OSU Cascades Branch-Bend, 2003 (Box 10)
  - Oregon Uniting, 1999-2000 (Box 10)
  - Oregon University System-Office of Multicultural Affairs, 1996-1999 (Box 10)
  - Other Universities Diversity Plans, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Pan Asian Community Alliance, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Portland State University Strategic Planning, 1991-1993 (Box 10)
  - President’s Board of Visitors for Minority Affairs, 1998 (Box 10)
  - Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS) Scare-Discrimination Toward Asians, 2003 (Box 10)
  - Statistical Profiles of the Four Minority Groups-Campus Presence, 1996-1997 (Box 10)
  - Student Action with Farmworkers Summer Internship and Leadership Development Program, 1993 (Box 10)
  - Student and Staff Ethnicity Information, 2001-2003 (Box 10)
  - Third World/Minority Academics in Oregon Group, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Understanding Racism Foundation, 2004 (Box 10)
  - University of Oregon Office of Multicultural Review Committee, 2004 (Box 10)
- Publications, 1992-2004; Series XI
  In addition to guides produced by the Office of Multicultural Affairs for advising Native American and other students of color, the publications in series XI include flyers for presentations and forums on multicultural issues and a handbook on child care published by the State of Oregon with editorial comments by Lee.
  - Flyers for Presentations and Events, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Guides to Services, Programs, and Resources for American Indian and Alaskan Native Students, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Multicultural Resource Guides for Advising Students of Color, 1993-2004 (Box 10)
  - Oregon Child Care Basics II: Social and Emotional Health Handbook, 1992 (Box 10)
    Includes comments Lee made as a reviewer of the document.
- Student Papers, 2001; Series XII
  Series XII consists of an an undergraduate honors thesis, Opening Minds and Opening Doors for Students of Color at OSU, detailing the organizational structure of the Office of Multicultural Affairs and its role in serving as a hub for diversity programs at the university.
- Off-Campus Organizations and Committees, 1991-2004; Series XIII
  Series XIII documents Lee’s involvement in non-OSU committees, professional associations, governmental bodies, and advisory councils. The organizations represented in this series are primarily state and regional entities oriented toward diversity and educational development. In addition to meeting minutes and correspondence, this series also contains reports, notes, newspaper clippings, and conference materials.
  - American Association of University Administrators, 1994-2003; 6 folders (Box 11)
  - Benton County Health Department Safety Net Committee, 2002-2003 (Box 11)
  - Benton County Needs Assessment Committee, 1999 (Box 11)
  - Building a Hate-Free Oregon Summit-Benton County/OSU Group, 1992-1993 (Box 11)
  - Center for Organizational Research and Development, 1992 (Box 11)
  - Community Alliance for Diversity, 1993-2003; 9 folders (Box 11)
  - Corvallis Partnerships for Diversity, 2004 (Box 11)
  - Council on Diversity in Education, 1992-2001; 2 folders
    - 1992-1994, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - 1994-2001, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Ethnic Cultures Consortium of Oregon, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
  - HIV Prevention Outreach for Women in Benton County Community Advisory Panel, 1997-1999 (Box 12)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges: Commission on Human Resources and Change, 1994-2003; 6 folders (Box 12)
  - Oregon Coalition for Inclusive Campuses, 1998 (Box 12)
  - Oregon Commission on Asian Affairs-Corvallis Area Advisory Committee, 1995-1996 (Box 12)
  - Oregon Cultural Trust-Community Cultural Planning Steering Committee, 2002 (Box 12)
  - Oregon Health Policy Institute-Underserved Populations Policy Workgroup, 1993-1995 (Box 12)
  - Oregon State Bar-Affirmative Action Forum Group, 1995-1998 (Box 12)
  - Oregon University System Multicultural Issues Group, 2001 (Box 12)
  - Oregon University System Native American Policy Work Group, 2001 (Box 12)
  - Statewide Students of Color Task Force, 1997 (Box 12)
  - Steering Committee on Diversity in Oregon’s Educational Reform, 1992; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Superintendent’s Advisory Committee on Ethnic Diversity, 1997-2000; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Teacher Standards and Practices Commission-Redesign Committee, 1997 (Box 12)
  - Teacher Standards and Practices Commission-Supply and Demand Committee (State of Oregon), 1997-1998 (Box 12)
  - Thomason Auto Group-Community Advisory Committee, 2001-2002 (Box 12)
  - Western Governor’s University-Oregon Advisory Committee, 1996 (Box 12)
- Harassment Incident Files, 1992-2002; Series XIV
  Series XIV pertains to complaints of racial and ethnic harassment from students at OSU and local high schools that were received by Phyllis Lee. Documenting situations both on campus and off, this series includes correspondence, flyers, incident reports, newspaper clippings, notes, sketches, and a banner.
  Access to these materials is restricted and subject to review by the reference archivist.
  - Off-Campus, 1992-1998 (Box 13)
  - On-Campus, 1992-2002 (Box 13)
- Photographs, 1991; Series XV (Box 14)
  The photographs (color prints and negatives) depict a performance of various international dances including the Chinese “dragon dance” in a grand opening ceremony commemorating the establishment of the Office of Multicultural Affairs in 1991.